GEORGE APAZIDIS

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

geoapa@gmail.com (203) 247-1348 Norwalk, CT GitHub LinkedIn Portfolio

Summary

Front-End Web Developer with a strong UX background. Experience working with a multitude of platforms, applications and programming languages (React, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (ES6), AJAX, Adobe Creative Suite) and comfortable with all technical, creative, and marketing aspects of the web.

Skills

Front End: React, JavaScript (ES6), HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, Bootstrap, NPM

Back End: RESTful APIs

Additional Tools: Git, GitHub, Slack, Jira, AEM, Photoshop, Illustrator

Recent Projects

Portfolio Site | GitHub: A responsive site highlighting the projects I developed.

<u>San Diego Quiz</u> | <u>GitHub</u>: A single page app that quizzes the user about San Diego. Built with HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript (ES6)

<u>Dog Search</u> | <u>GitHub</u>: A single page web app that provides dog breed information. Built with HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, and AJAX. Uses the YouTube, Wikipedia, and dog.ceo APIs.

Experience

SELF EMPLOYED Freelance Web Developer

Norwalk, CT

September 2018 – Current

- Consult for a digital marketing agency, Out and About Communications, performing website updates to client sites
 using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and PHP.
- Research and integrate appropriate WordPress plugins and various analytics code snippets.
- Collaborate with project managers and other developers by using Asana and Slack.

LEGG MASON

Stamford, CT

Front-End Web Developer & UX Specialist

April 2013 - August 2018

- Developed responsive web pages and components by leveraging various JavaScript libraries and CSS frameworks.
- Coded clean cross-browser, semantic code with a focus on SEO and usability.
- Increased level of expertise on the team by leading weekly training sessions with junior developers.
- Collaborated with back-end developers, designers, product owners by attending meetings and using Jira.
- Studied and became proficient in website usability by completing formal training and earning a UX certificate.
- Consulted as a UX expert on new website launches by performing usability tests and heuristic evaluations.

dLife Westport, CT

Front-End Web Developer

July 2012 - March 2013

- Developed web components using clean, semantic code that met the W3C validation standards.
- Refactored old legacy code by identifying and fixing errors using browser developer tools and code validation apps.
- Performed thorough cross-browser compatibility testing.

BOEHRINGER INGELHEIM Danbury, CT

Front-End Web Developer

2010 - 2011

- Developed web pages from layered Photoshop files by using XHTML and CSS.
- Developed interactive components using jQuery and AJAX.

SELF EMPLOYED Norwalk, CT

Freelance Web Consultant

2009 – 2010

- Developed several web sites by using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and XML.
- Executed SEO and PPC campaigns resulting in much larger search engine exposure and traffic.
- Corrected SEO issues such as crawl errors and canonical issues by using Google Console.

GE REAL ESTATE Norwalk, CT

E-media Communications Specialist

2005 – 2008

- Developed new websites by using HTML, JavaScript and Flash while collaborating with various business units around the world.
- Trained and led a team of content managers resulting in more efficient and prompt website updates.

TECHNOLOGY MARKETING CORPORATION

Norwalk, CT

Web Designer/Developer and SEO Specialist

2004 - 2005

- Designed and developed custom web portals with a strong focus on SEO.
- Developed custom ASP.net scripts and supported a senior developer while staffing level was low.

Education

THINKFUL.COM CODING BOOTCAMP

Currently enrolled

Full-Stack Web Development Program / Engineering Immersion

- Learning industry best practices and practical software development standards with a focus on HTML5, CSS3,
 JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, React, Redux, and algorithms & data structures.
- Created and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks by collaborating several hours every week with a senior web developer.

ROCHESTER INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

BS, Information Technology, Website Development Concentration

2002